

## **SKILLS**

- IFRS awareness
- Office 365
- Microsoft Excel
- Audit coordination
- Accounting operations professional
- Budget analysis
- Financial reporting
- Closing processes
- Advanced bookkeeping skills

#### **EDUCATION**

**Mansoura University** | *Egypt* Bachelor of Commerce: Accounting

Member of SOCPA

### **LANGUAGES**

**Arabic** 

Native

**English** 

Advanced

### **PERSONAL DETAILS**

Date of Birth / Age: 25-7-1991 Nationality: EGYPTION Marital Status: Married



# Mohammed Gamal Hemdan

- 0568070872 0532806731
- m.hemdan1@outlook.sa
- Riyadh, Riyadh Region 111
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/mohammed-hemdan-29240b8a/

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Seasoned Accountant bringing more than [10] years of experience directing accounting systems for diverse business groups. Industrious and cost-conscious with excellent project management abilities. Advanced understanding of industry standards and accounting laws, expert with many (ERP) systems like SAP, ONEX ....etc

#### **WORK HISTORY**

01/2016 - Current

Chief Accountant

Foodunitco | Riyadh, Riyadh Region.













- Set up and improved accounting systems and processes to meet business needs and maximize operational success.
- Completed year-end closing processes with controllers and external auditors.
- Calculated tax owed, prepared, and submitted returns and upheld compliance with all applicable laws.
- Reviewed budgets and communicated discrepancies to senior management.
- Controlled costs to keep business operating within budget and increase profits.
- Assisted team members in transitioning to new system through extensive training and one-on-one support.
- Reviewed business operations and obligations to help organization function at acceptable level.
- Prepared accounts for industry audits and supported audit process.
- Handled month-end and year-end end finances by managing and reporting fixed assets and other data.
- Drafted variance reports, regulatory filings, and related schedules.
- Created quarterly and yearly balance sheets to track financial trends and performance.
- Maintained integrity of general ledger, including chart of accounts.
- Prepared monthly bank reconciliations with 100% accuracy.
- Reconciled accounts from income and expense data to net worth and assets.
- AnaAnalyzed lysed monthly balance sheet accounts for corporate reporting.
- Created periodic reports comparing budgeted costs to actual costs.







- Checked and imported payroll data to pay salary and set accruals for all employees.
- Reported suspicious transactions and unusual account activity to appropriate escalation channels.
- Resolved reporting errors by conducting investigations and amending accounting entries in line with regulations.
- Produced and presented detailed monthly accounting reports to [CFO].
- Set up payment plans for suppliers with other departments.
- Prepare cost for a new product.

#### 01/2013 - 01/2016

#### **Financial Accountant**

#### Elmemary Elsaudi | Jeddah

- Completed year-end closing processes with controllers and external auditors.
- Prepared monthly journal entries and reconciliations.
- Handled month-end and year-end end finances by managing and reporting fixed assets and other data.
- Managed projects through budgeting, scheduling and complex problemsolving.
- Determined problem areas and resolved issues related to profitability and business objective achievement.
- Prepared detailed models, reports and charts highlighting complex financial information.
- Assisted with developing and ongoing control of costing and pricing systems for business goods.
- Compiled general ledger entries on short schedule with 100% accuracy.
- Organized and carried out month-end, quarterly and year-end processes.
- Advised management on financial details related to business operations, inventory levels and budgets.
- Resolved invoice coding and tracked recurring expenses for accrual entry.
- Trained new employees on accounting principles and company procedures.
- Managed financial updates, watch lists and insurance files.
- Compiled financial data for business forecasting and budgeting.
- Generated invoices based on established accounts receivable schedules and terms.
- Tracked tax, invoicing, and budget information accurately using OuickBooks.
- Reviewed and certified official financial statements for presentation to shareholders and governing bodies.
- Installed internal controls and set up standard procedures for business accounting systems.
- Reconciled account information and reported figures in general ledger by comparing to bank account statements each month.
- Participated in weekly meetings to discuss goals and areas of improvement.

#### 2012 - 2013

#### **Accountant**

# ITC Academy -Egypt

- Post and process journal entries to ensure all business transactions are recorded.
- Update accounts receivable and issue invoices
- Update accounts payable and perform reconciliations.

## **SKILLS**

- Organization
- •Time management
  - Adaptability
  - Communication
    - Openness
    - Leadership

- Assist in the processing of balance sheets, income statements and other financial statements according to legal and company accounting and financial guidelines.
- Assist with reviewing of expenses, payroll records etc. as assigned.
- Update financial data in databases to ensure that information will be accurate and immediately available when needed.
- Prepare and submit weekly/monthly reports.
- Assist senior accountants in the preparation of monthly/yearly closings.
- Assist with other accounting projects.

## **ACCOMPLISHMENTS**

- Achieved [reduce cost] through effectively helping with recosting the product, down more than 3%.
- Supervised team of [3] staff members.
- Used Microsoft Excel to develop inventory tracking spreadsheets.

## **AFFILIATIONS**

• IMA | Institute of Management Accountants (CMA)

Part 1 (pass)

Part 2 (In Progress)

• Corporate Finance Institute® (CFI)

Issued Aug 2021Issued Aug 2021

Credential ID 37604927

• International Business Management Institute (IBMI)

Issued Aug 2021Issued Aug 2021

Credential ID 448893-163-014-5068

Financial Performance

SOCPA

الهيئة السعودية للمر اجعين والمحاسبين Issued Feb 2020

Credential ID 55349

• ICDL UN

# **COURSES**

Course Name	Training Center	Course content
CMA (Certified Management Accountant)	CMA in progress	Control Financial Planning, and Performance & Financial Decision Making
ICDL (un) - Confirmation number un 1011204	ICDeL un	International Computer Driving License
Diploma in English Language	American International Academy (AIA)	Speak & writing - level 10
Course in accounting program (oracle financial)	HARVEST EGYPT	Method of using the accounting program
Course in QuickBooks	HARVEST EGYPT	Method of using the accounting program
Course in Peachtree program	HARVEST EGYPT	Method of using the accounting program
Course in bookkeeping and budgeting	HARVEST EGYPT	bookkeeping and budgeting
Course in accounting on Excel	International Training Academy and Consulting	Excel accounting and American Journal and sub accounts.
Accounting course in English	International Training Academy and Consulting	Accounting in English
A course in sales and point of sale by DEXF Program	self-education	Method of using the accounting program
Course in programs of networks, and mikrotik	self-education	Network maintenance
SAP Business One	Tyconz KSA	Finance & logistic